YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series V. Program Subjects
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. PROGRAM SUBJECTS
  - Subseries D. Pageantry and Drama
    - Scripts
      - "The Receiving Line: A Skit on National Support" by Barbara Abel, given at regional conferences, 1951 (Box 643, Folder 21)
      - Red Letter Day Plays by Margaret Getchell Parsons, TWP, 1924 (Box 643, Folder 22)
      - "Rehearsal at 7:00" by Barbara Abel, TWP, 1935 (Box 644, Folder 1)
      - "Relationships, Real and Reflected," St. Paul, Minnesota, YWCA Volunteer Leadership Committee, 1959 (Box 644, Folder 2)
      - "The Rescue and Sea Sand: Two Water Pantomimes" by Lucy South Proudfoot, TWP, 1927 (Box 644, Folder 3)
      - "The Resurrection of Our Lord: A Protestant Miracle Play of the XVI Century found in the Malone Society Papers, 1912" adapted by May Pashley Harris, TWP, 1923 (Box 644, Folder 4)
      - "Right About Space!," 1953 (Box 644, Folder 5)
      - "The Road to Tomorrow: A Pageant-Play" by Josephine Thorp, 1920 (Box 644, Folder 6)
      - "Roped-In," honoring volunteers-1970 Annual Meeting, York, PA (Box 644, Folder 7)
      - "The Scarlet Knight: an Autumn Play" by Mary S. Edgar, TWP, 1920 (Box 644, Folder 8)
      - "Scene in Buenos Aires Association Office," pageant, 1911(?) (Box 644, Folder 9)
      - "Scenes and Songs of Home: A Pantomime" by Marion Norris Gleason, TWP, 1919 (Box 644, Folder 10)
      - "The Search: A Pageant-Drama" by Helen Louise Robinson, TWP, 1936 (Box 644, Folder 11)
      - "Serving Women Who Fight for Freedom," radio script, [1943] (Box 644, Folder 12)
      - "The Shining Goddess: A Health Pageant" by Clara E. Sackett, TWP, 1920 (Box 644, Folder 13)
      - "The Shoe on the Other Foot" by Barbara Abel, 1932 (Box 644, Folder 14)
      - "The Shoestring Express" by Barbara Abel, 18th National Convention, 1949 (Box 644, Folder 15)
      - "Signs of the Times: Presenting Various Phases of Association Activities" by Barbara Abel, TWP, 1937 (Box 644, Folder 16)
      - "The Silent Voice: A pageant-play for spring and summer production out-of-doors, or for indoor use at any time of year" by Olive Jones, TWP, 1924 (Box 644, Folder 17)
      - Skits Kit,1967 (Box 644, Folder 18)
      - "The Sleeping Princess: a May Day Masque from Many Lands" by Dorothy Gladys Spicer, TWP, 1929 (Box 644, Folder 19)
      - "The Snow Queen: A Fairy Play for Children in Two Acts" by Elizabeth B. Grimball, TWP, 1920 (Box 644, Folder 20)
      - "Songs of the Living: A Community of Faith Through Song" by Lucy Schulte, TWP, 1944 (Box 644, Folder 21)
      - "Space Skit" by Mrs. Ralph D. Booth for Gala Dinner, National Convention, Mar 1958 (Box 644, Folder 22)
      - "The Spirit of Cooperation: A Playlet in 3 Acts" by Lydia Johnson and Louise K. Stoll, 1922 (Box 644, Folder 23)
      - "The Spirit of Labor" by Mary E. Dreier, TWP, Program Series no. 30, ca. 1924 (Box 644, Folder 24)
      - "The Spirit of Sisterhood" by Helen Santmyer, 1915 (Box 644, Folder 25)
      - "Spring or The Queen of Youth: A Pageant" by Edith Roeder Jacobs, TWP, 1925 (Box 644, Folder 26)
      - "Spirit of the Y," High Point, North Carolina, Annual Dinner, 1968 (Box 644, Folder 27)
      - "Students in Crisis," 1960s? (Box 644, Folder 28)
      - "Subcommittee on Brass Tacks" a skit prepared for the opening of All-Convention Discussion Groups, 19th National Convention, May 1952 by Barbara Abel (Box 644, Folder 29)
      - "The Tapestry Weavers: Honor Court Play" given originally by the Girl Reserve Department, Detroit, MI, YWCA, TWP program series, 1930 (Box 644, Folder 30)
      - "Ten Timely Dances" by Helen Durham and Janet Lane, TWP, 1924 (Box 644, Folder 31)
      - "Ten Years of Hands" by Eva A. Moore, Oakland Branch YWCA, 1970 (Box 644, Folder 32)
      - "That's Inevitable: A Play in Three Episodes" created by the Drama Interest Group, Southern Industrial Conference, 1929 (Box 644, Folder 33)
      - "There Ain't No Jestice: A Play of a Cotton Mill Town in Carolina" by W.S. Fewell, TWP, 1930 (Box 644, Folder 34)
      - "There is a Choice" by Lucy Schulte, School for Professional Workers, 1954 (Box 644, Folder 35)
      - "There is a Lad Here" by Belle MacDiarmid Ritchey, TWP, 1925 (Box 644, Folder 36)
      - "These Things Shall Be" by Brooks Spivy, TWP, 1939 (Box 645, Folder 1)
      - "The Thirteen Colonies: A Patriotic Pageant" by Magdelene Craft Rodke, TWP, 1926 (Box 645, Folder 2)
      - "This is Remembrance: An Easter Playlet" by Christine P'Simer, TWP [1942] (Box 645, Folder 3)
      - "Three Ceremonials" reprinted from The Bookshelf, Sep-Oct 1947 (Box 645, Folder 4)
      - "Three Household Employment Playlets," TWP, 1941 (Box 645, Folder 5)
      - "Three Pantomimes" by Era Bentzer, TWP third printing, 1937 (Box 645, Folder 6)
      - "Through Other Eyes: A World Fellowship Project in Dramatic Form" by Helen D. Beavers, TWP, 1930 (Box 645, Folder 7)
      - "Through the Blue Triangle: A Pageant" by Josephine Thorp, TWP, 1919 (Box 645, Folder 8)
      - "Through the Centuries: A Pageant of American Women in Industry," 1920 (Box 645, Folder 9)
      - "Thursday Off" by Barbara Abel, n.d. (Box 645, Folder 10)
      - "The Times Demand: a dramatic poem arranged for chorus and readers by Lucy Schulte, TWP, 1945 (Box 645, Folder 11)
      - "To Sing With the Stars: A Song of the Peoples of the Earth" by Lucy Schulte, TWP program packet, fall 1949 (Box 645, Folder 12)
      - "To Work as One" a report in dramatic form of the first World's YWCA Membership Conference, Aug 1950, by Lucy Schulte (Box 645, Folder 13)
      - "The Torch Bearers of the Western World" by Elizabeth B. Grimball, 1920 (Box 645, Folder 14)
      - "The Tree of Life: An Easter Pageant" by Esther Willard Bates, TWP, 1922 (Box 645, Folder 15)
      - "The Triumph of Spring: a Festival of Old World Songs and Ceremonial Customs" by Dorothy Gladys Spicer, TWP, 1923 (Box 645, Folder 16)
      - "The Trouble That Is In It" adapted from Eleanor's Enterprise by G. A. Birmingham, TWP, 1919 (Box 645, Folder 17)
      - "Two Indian Legends" dramatized for children by Frances Densmore, TWP, 1926 (Box 645, Folder 18)
      - "Two Water Pageants for Swimming Classes in Association, Camp, or School" by Lucy South Proudfoot, TWP, 1924 (Box 645, Folder 19)
      - "The Two-Way Street or Mr. Brass Tacks in Charge of Facts" by Mabel Alice Tuggle, 1961 (Box 645, Folder 20)
      - "Two Weeks With Pay: A Midsummer Day-Dream" by Barbara Abel, TWP, 1924 (Box 645, Folder 21)
      - "United We Stand: A Festival of the Nation" by Josephine Thorp, TWP, 1919 (Box 645, Folder 22)
      - "Venus: A Dance Drama" by Edith Roeder Jacobs, TWP, 1926, 1942 (Box 645, Folder 23)
      - "The Victory of Light: A Masque" by Helen L. Willcox, TWP, 1926 (Box 645, Folder 24)
      - "The Vision of the Blue Crusaders: A Pageant" by Sue Ann Wilson, TWP, 1919 (Box 645, Folder 25)
      - "Voices" by Harriet C. (Mrs. George B.) Ford, given at the Cause and Cure of War Conference, 1931, TWP, 1931, 1937 (Box 645, Folder 26)
      - "Voices, Women's Voices…" by Emma Christie Smith Stephens for the 125th Birthday Celebration of the YWCA, 1984 (Box 645, Folder 27)
      - "Void if Detached: A YWCA Membership Skit in One Act" by Barbara Abel, n.d. (Box 645, Folder 28)
      - "A Wage Controversy (A Mock Trial" written by the Denver Industrial Group, TWP, 1930 (Box 646, Folder 1)
      - "The Wayside Piper" by Mary S. Edgar, TWP, 1923 (Box 646, Folder 2)
      - "What a Relief! for finance workers, committees and all those who must appear before the public on behalf of the YWCA yearly budget" by Barbara Abel, TWP, 1935 (Box 646, Folder 3)
      - "What the Moon Lady Sees: an International Harvest Festival" by Dorothy Gladys Spicer, TWP, 1929 (Box 646, Folder 4)
      - "Where Do We Go From Here?" by Barbara Abel, The Woman's Press, Apr 1949 (Box 646, Folder 5)
      - "Which Way Out? A Program for a China Evening" by Florence Wells, TWP, 1919 (Box 646, Folder 6)
      - "Who Knows Mrs. Powers?" by Barbara Kay Davidson, an American Theatre Wing Community Play written and produced for the YWCA of the USA with specially written discussion leads, 1958 (Box 646, Folder 7)
      - "Who'll Buy Democracy?" by Barbara Abel, The Womans Press, Jul-Aug 1939 (Box 646, Folder 8)
      - "Why-Phyllis Wheatley? A Ceremonial Interpretation" by Dorothy C. Guinn, TWP program series no. XVIII, 1924 (Box 646, Folder 9)
      - "Widening Our Reach: Student-Industrial Play" TWP program series XXII, 1924 (Box 646, Folder 10)
      - "The Wise and the Foolish Virgins" a dramatization of the parable as found in the 25th chapter of Saint Matthew by Marjorie Lacey-Baker, TWP program series XIX, 1923 (Box 646, Folder 11)
      - "Within the Four Seas: a presentation of the foreign program of the YWCA" and "A St. John's Eve Celebration" by Jean Grigsby Paxton, TWP Program Series no. 5, 1926 (Box 646, Folder 12)
      - "The Wohpe Festival: being an all-day celebration, consisting of ceremonials, games, dances and songs, in honor of Wohpe, one of the four Superior Gods of the Dakota pagan religion, and Goddess of nature and Patroness of games, of adornment, and of little children" arranged especially for schools and summer camps by Ella Cara Deloria (Yahn-ka) of the Yankton Band of Dakota Sioux, TWP, 1932 (Box 646, Folder 13)
      - "The Woman's Press Skit" by Margot Gayle, n.d. (Box 646, Folder 14)
      - "Wonderland of the Y's World" by Alison Harrison, TWP, 1939 (Box 646, Folder 15)
      - "Wooings and Witches: A Shakespearean Medley" by Vida R. Sutton, TWP, 1925 (Box 646, Folder 16)
      - "A Word to the Y's" a stunt for annual meetings, banquets and membership nights to present the work of the Association by Barbara Abel, TWP program series XI, 1924 (Box 646, Folder 17)
      - "The World Circle" by Mary L. Carr and "Wide Open Windows" by Emma Knauss and Frances Perry, TWP program series no. XIII, 1924 (Box 646, Folder 18)
      - "X.B.M. Revue (All Star Cast-offs)" by Mary Booth, 1958 (Box 646, Folder 19)
      - Yelenka the Wise and Other Folk Tales in Dramatic Form by Anne Charlotte Darlington, TWP, 1926 (Box 646, Folder 20)
      - "Y-olanthe: A Co-operative Opera" adapted from Gilbert and Sullivan's "Iolanthe" to meet the crying demands of YWCA-YMCA Cooperation. Music by Sir Arthur Sullivan, Words by Barbara Abel, 1929 (Box 646, Folder 21-22)
      - "The YWCA Budget and Community Chest Hearing," skit used at Regional Conferences, 1948 (Box 646, Folder 23)
      - "The YWCA Herstory," 1976 (Box 646, Folder 24)
      - "The YWCA is on the March," Mid-Peninsula YWCA, 1967 (Box 646, Folder 25)
      - "YWCA Staff Report to the Board," Allentown, PA, skit, 1970 (Box 646, Folder 26)
      - "YWCA Treasure Chest," TWP program series no. 46, 1927 (Box 646, Folder 27)
    - Christmas Scripts
      - "Big Sister's Christmas Dream: A Holiday Play for Girls" by Dorothy Powell, 1919 (Box 646, Folder 28)
      - "The Brightness of His Rising: A Christmas Miracle Play" by Margaret Lynch Conger, TWP, 1924 (Box 646, Folder 29)
      - "Bringers of Gifts" by Era Betzner, TWP Program Series no. XX, 1924 (Box 646, Folder 30)
      - "Christ is Born in Bethlehem: A Play of the Nativity" by Vida R. Sutton, TWP, 1928, 1942 (Box 646, Folder 31)
      - "A Christmas Book: A Christmas Playlet for Children" by May E. Phipps and Marjorie Van Horn, TWP, 1925 (Box 647, Folder 1)
      - "Christmas Carols" by Margaret Parsons, TWP, 1929 (Box 647, Folder 2)
      - "A Christmas Dilemma" Lancaster (PA) Association, TWP, 1920 (Box 647, Folder 3)
      - "The Christmas Message" adapted by Lucy T. Bartlett from the play in "Red Letter Day Plays" by Margaret Getchell Parsons, TWP 1927 (Box 647, Folder 4)
      - "A Christmas Miracle Play" by Doris Gundry, TWP, 1931 (Box 647, Folder 5)
      - "The Christmas of the Little Pines: A Holiday Playlet with Songs" by Emma Mauritz Larson, music by Margaret Hicks, TWP, 1931 (Box 647, Folder 6)
      - "Christmas Scenes in Other Lands: Pantomimes with Songs and Carols" by Julia Phillips Ruopp, TWP, 1937 (Box 647, Folder 7)
      - "The Christmas Sheaf" by Emma Mauritz Larson, TWP, 1931 (Box 647, Folder 8)
      - "The Christmas Story: a Group of Tableaux" by Jane Taylor Miller, 1915, TWP, 1926 (Box 647, Folder 9)
      - "The Christmas Tree Bluebird" by Mary S. Edgar, TWP, 1920 (Box 647, Folder 10)
      - "A Christmas Trilogy" by Ellen Dunwoody Nester, TWP, 1938 (Box 647, Folder 11)
      - "Chug's Challenge" by Emma Mauritz Larson, TWP, 1931 (Box 647, Folder 12)
      - "The First Nowell: A play for Christmas-tide, in three scenes, which are adapted from the Mediaeval Nativity plays, and with a prologue and epilogue" by Claudine E. Clement, TWP, 1928, 1942 (Box 647, Folder 13)
      - "Guiding Light: A Nativity Play" by Ivy Bolton, TWP, 1927 (Box 647, Folder 14)
      - "The Journey of the Three Wise Men" by Anna R. Kennedy, TWP, 1937 (Box 647, Folder 15)
      - "The Least of These: A Christmas Play" by Ella M. Wilson and Anna W. Field, TWP, 1923, 1928, 1943 (Box 647, Folder 16)
      - "The Little Princess Who Traveled Far to Worship the King" by Dorothy R. Schenk, 5th printing 1942 (Box 647, Folder 17)
      - "The Man Who Gave Us Christmas" by Edith Newlin and others, TWP, 1941 (Box 647, Folder 18)
      - "Marcus: A Story in Pantomime for Christmas" by Edith K. Olson, TWP, 1936 (Box 647, Folder 19)
      - "The Miser's Mill" by Ednah Proctor Clarke with incidental music by Julia Proctor White, TWP, 1919 (Box 647, Folder 20)
      - "The Nativity of the Manger: A Christmas Tableaux" by Helen Durham, TWP, 1928 (Box 647, Folder 21)
      - "The News That Came to Nazareth: A Mystery Play" by Ivy Bolton, TWP 1936 (Box 647, Folder 22)
      - "The Pearl Merchant: A Christmas Play" by Anna R. Kennedy, TWP, 1941 (Box 647, Folder 23)
      - "St. Francis of Assisi: A Christmas masque in one act" by Margaret Lynch Conger, TWP, 1924 (Box 647, Folder 24)
      - "The Spirit of Christmas" by Grace E. Craig, TWP, 1920 (Box 647, Folder 25)
      - "Such Loving Kindness! A Christmas Story in Three Parts" by Annie B. Kerr, TWP, 1940 (Box 647, Folder 26)
      - "Then Deck the Halls" by Miriam Rightmire Epps, TWP, 1938 (Box 647, Folder 27)
      - "This Side of Heaven" by Martha French, n.d. (Box 647, Folder 28)
      - "Told in All Tongues: The American Christmas" by Lucy Schulte, TWP, 1941 (Box 647, Folder 29)
      - "To Whom Christ Came: A Play of the Nativity in Three Scenes" by Mary B. Jones, TWP, 1931 (Box 647, Folder 30)
      - "Three Christmas Wishes" by Caroline deF. Penniman, TWP 1926 (Box 647, Folder 31)
      - "A Traditional Christmas: A One-Act Play for High School Girls" by Ruth S. Gibson, TWP, 1942 (Box 647, Folder 32)
      - "The Transfiguration of the Gifts" by Frances Cavanah, TWP 1923 (Box 647, Folder 33)
      - "The Waif: A Christmas Morality of the Twentieth Century" by Elizabeth B. Grimball, TWP, n.d. (Box 647, Folder 34)
      - "Yuletide in Other Lands: A Christmas Pageant" by Mary W. Hillyer and "The Hanging of the Greens: A Fantasy to Precede the Holiday Season" by Mrs. Arthur Withington, TWP, 1927 (Box 647, Folder 35)
      - "Yuletide Wakes, Yuletide Breaks: A Holiday Revel of Many Lands" by Dorothy Gladys Spicer, TWP, 1927 (Box 647, Folder 36)
  - Subseries E. Religion
    - General and History: the YWCA as a Christian organization
      - General, 1913-87 (Box 648, Folder 1-3)
      - "The Relationship between the Theological Position of the Y.W.C.A. and Its Position on Social Issues between 1906 and 1949," Margaret Cuenod, paper, 1949 (Box 648, Folder 4)
      - "The Social Gospel" by Frances James, paper, 1974 (Box 648, Folder 5)
      - Catholic Church: reports, histories, printed material, press releases, 1947-68, n.d., [see also Committee on Protestant-Catholic relations] (Box 648, Folder 6)
      - Discussion Guides, 1920s-43 (Box 648, Folder 7)
      - Commission to Study the YWCA as a Christian Movement
        - Meeting reports, 1964-65 (Box 648, Folder 8-9)
        - Guide, 1965-67 (Box 648, Folder 10)
        - Reports, recommendations, and pamphlets, 1966-67 (Box 648, Folder 11)
      - Study of the [Christian] "Purpose"
        - Meeting materials, 1972-75 (Box 648, Folder 12)
        - Reference materials, 1958-75, n.d. (Box 648, Folder 13)
      - Practices Regarding Religion in 52 Community YWCAs in the Eastern Region, Data and Statistics department report, 1957 (Box 648, Folder 14)
    - Committees
      - Joint Committee on Religious Program of the Department of Method, 1916 (Box 649, Folder 1)
      - Council/Committee on Religion
        - General: bulletin, charter, speech, 1942-44 (Box 649, Folder 2)
        - Minutes, 1929-44 (Box 649, Folder 3)
      - Religious education: minutes, reports, and bibliography, 1915-20 (Box 649, Folder 4)
      - Religious work committee: minutes, 1917-20 (Box 649, Folder 5)
      - Protestant-Catholic Relations: minutes and reports, 1941-43 (Box 649, Folder 6)
      - New Society and Its Christian Basis: minutes, reports, and conference materials, 1942-43 (Box 649, Folder 7)
      - Religious Resources Group: clipping and report, 1962-68 (Box 649, Folder 8)
      - Liberation task force
        - General: correspondence, minutes, 1971-76 (Box 649, Folder 9)
        - Bicentennial Conference on Religious Liberty: minutes and correspondence, 1974 (Box 649, Folder 10)
      - Committee to Study the Purpose
        - Meeting materials, 1989 (Box 649, Folder 11)
        - Ballots and discussion guide, 1991 (Box 649, Folder 12)
        - Leader/Facilitator instructions and guidelines for YWCA Purpose videotape, "The Purpose Study Session," 1990 (Box 649, Folder 13)
    - Organizations [outside Y]: Committee on War and Religious Outlook, pamphlets, 1919-20 (Box 649, Folder 14)
    - Reference material
      - Bibliographies and reviews, 1928, 1989 (Box 649, Folder 15)
      - Printed material, 1919-80, n.d. (Box 649, Folder 16-17)
    - Publications and Resource Materials
      - General
        - The Bible and Human Rights by Kathleen W. MacArthur, 1948; revised edition, 1949 (Box 649, Folder 18)
        - The Christian Approach to Social Morality by Richard C. Cabot, 1913 (Box 650, Folder 1)
        - Christian Citizenship for Girls by Helen Thoburn, 1924 (Box 650, Folder 2)
        - The Christian Faith and My Job report and study guide on the International Study Conference, 1957 (Box 650, Folder 3)
        - Christian Faith and Social Action by Rose Terlin, 1940 (Box 650, Folder 4)
        - Christian Fundamentals by Oolooah Burner, 1921 (Box 650, Folder 5)
        - The Christmas Guest by Annie B. Kerr, 1944 (Box 650, Folder 6)
        - The Democracy We Defend edited by Elizabeth B. Herring, 1942 (Box 650, Folder 7)
        - Eternal Life Begins Now by Kathleen W. MacArthur, 1942 (Box 650, Folder 8)
        - Faith for Reconstruction by Rose Terlin, 1941 (Box 650, Folder 9)
        - The Faiths of Mankind by Edmund Davison Soper, 1918 (Box 650, Folder 10)
        - Ferment of Freedom by Letty M. Russell, 1972 (Box 650, Folder 11)
        - Girlhood and Character by Mary E. Moxcey, 1916 (Box 650, Folder 12)
        - God by J.E. Boodin, 1930 (Box 650, Folder 13)
        - The Good Life-A Discipline by Winnifred Wygal, 1941 (Box 650, Folder 14)
        - Handbook for Ministers' Wives by Welthy Honsinger Fisher, 1950 (Box 651, Folder 1)
        - How Christian Is the Church? by Dorothy Height and Winnifred Wygal, 1937 (Box 651, Folder 2)
        - The Human Element in the Making of a Christian: Studies in Personal Evangelism by Bertha Conde, 1917 (Box 651, Folder 3)
        - "I Believe in God..." by Anna V. Rice, 1934 (Box 651, Folder 4)
        - Jesus' Way with People by Alexander C. Purdy, 1926 (Box 651, Folder 5)
        - Jewish Holidays-Do You Know Them? by Elise F. Moller, 1946 (Box 651, Folder 6)
        - Lady in the Pulpit by Laura Kerr, 1951 (Box 651, Folder 7)
        - Life Is Commitment, 1955 (Box 651, Folder 8)
        - Life that Is Life Indeed by Harold Cooke Phillips, 1928 (Box 651, Folder 9)
        - The Meaning of the Evolutionary Process: The Divine Problem as Seen by a Christian Theist by Edmund B. Chaffee, 1927 (Box 652, Folder 1)
        - New Frontiers for Faith by Charles W. Gilkey, 1927 (Box 652, Folder 2)
        - On, to the City of God by Richard Roberts, 1921 (Box 652, Folder 3)
        - Opportunity for Religion by Harry F. Ward, 1919 (Box 652, Folder 4)
        - Our Religious Vocabulary by Winnifred Wygal1939 (Box 652, Folder 5)
        - Pathways to God by Alexander Purdy, 1922 (Box 652, Folder 6)
        - Patriotism and the Christian Life by Wilfrid A. Rowell, 1918 (Box 652, Folder 7)
        - The Philosophy of Missions by Rev. G.A. Johnstron Ross, 1908 (Box 652, Folder 8)
        - Potters and Pipers by Oolooah Burner, 1924 (Box 652, Folder 9)
        - A Present Day Definition of Christianity by Laura H. Wild, 1920 (Box 652, Folder 10)
        - Primer for Protestants by James Hastings Nichols, 1947 (Box 652, Folder 11)
        - Questions and Answers about You by Tirzah Anderson and Winnifred Wygal, 1945 (Box 653, Folder 1)
        - The Religious Way by Gregory Vlastos, 1934 (Box 653, Folder 2)
        - Saints and Ladies by Clarissa Spencer, 1925 (Box 653, Folder 3)
        - So Gracious Is the Time by Annie B. Kerr, 1938 (Box 653, Folder 4)
        - Songs of Creation by Marion Cuthbert, 1949 (Box 653, Folder 5)
        - Stop, Think, and Do! by Elizabeth Palmer, Janet Fowler Nelson, and Winnifred Wygal, 1941 (Box 653, Folder 6)
        - Studies in the Life of Christ in Art by Marie Louise Slack, 1909 (Box 653, Folder 7)
        - The Superb Adventure by Winnifred Wygal, 1934 (Box 653, Folder 8)
        - Supply Lines for Morale by Kathleen MacArthur, 1942 (Box 653, Folder 9)
        - Such Loving Kindness! by Annie B. Kerr, 1940 (Box 653, Folder 10)
        - Things that Cannot Be Shaken by Charlotte H. Adams, 1918 (Box 653, Folder 11)
        - Three Studies for Discussion and Reflection: The Nature of Religion by Winnifred Wygal, 1936 (Box 653, Folder 12)
        - The Ultimate Quest: Discovering God in His World by Katherine Gerwick, 1920 (Box 653, Folder 13)
        - What's Best Worth Saying, by Rev. Richard Roberts, 1922 (Box 653, Folder 14)
        - Wings for the Commonplace, volumes I-IV, by Oolooah Burner, 1942 (Box 653, Folder 15)
        - Youth Asks about Religion by Jack Finegan, 1949 (Box 654, Folder 1)
        - Youth Searching by B.B.T., 1928 (Box 654, Folder 2)
      - YWCA religious program
        - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1907-17, 1947-62 (Box 654, Folder 3)
        - The Association as a Religious Movement in the World Today by Anna V. Rice, 1930 (Box 654, Folder 4)
        - Barrier-Breaking Love: A Plan for Member YWCAs to Study the Mission of the YWCA of the U.S.A., 1983 (Box 654, Folder 5)
        - Biblical Insights on the YWCA Purpose: A Leader's Guide for Use with Study-Discussion Groups, 1964 (Box 654, Folder 6)
        - Church and Association Cooperation by Augustus Nash, 1907 (Box 654, Folder 7)
        - Decision Making by Grace Loucks Elliott, 1958 [2nd ed. 1964] (Box 654, Folder 8)
        - Faith for the Job by Kathleen W. MacArthur, 1946 (Box 654, Folder 9)
        - From Deep Roots: The Story of the YWCA's Religious Dimensions by Frances Helen Mains and Grace Loucks Elliott, 1974 (Box 654, Folder 10)
        - From Faith to Action in the YWCA by Kathleen W. MacArthur, 1946 (Box 654, Folder 11)
        - Leadership Papers on Religion, 1957 (Box 654, Folder 12)
        - Life that Is Life Indeed by Harold Cooke Phillips, 1928 (Box 654, Folder 13)
        - Our Faith and Ourselves Today by Dr. Rollo May and Dr. John C. Bennett, 1955 (Box 654, Folder 14)
        - Our Heritage as Christians by Grace Loucks Elliott, 1958 (Box 654, Folder 15)